Preliminary Guide to the Social Democrats, USA Records, 1937-1994 (Bulk 1970-1994)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession 2001-0079
  - contents of Box 24: (Box 24)
    - SI: Issues Disarmament Appeal, 1984 (Box 24)
    - SI: Declaration of the Socialist International, 1951-1962 (Box 24)
    - SI: Disarmament Appeal, 1984 March 16 (Box 24)
    - SI: Disarmament Commission (Box 24)
    - SI: Disarmament, Helsinki, 1981 July 13 (Box 24)
    - SI: Dominican Republic (Box 24)
    - SI: Disarmament Study Group (Box 24)
    - SI: Dues, (two folders) (Box 24)
    - SI Congress, Speech By Paul Feldman, 1972 (Box 24)
    - SI Congress, Post Conference, report: Suall and Feldman, 1972 (Box 24)
    - SI: Congress Resolutions Committee. Bad Meiemajr, 1980 September 14 (Box 24)
    - SI Congress Vienna: N.Y. Luncheon, 1972 July 17 (Box 24)
    - SI: Cyprus (Box 24)
    - SI: Cuba (Box 24)
    - SI: Council Meeting, Madrid, 1988 May 11-12, (five folders) (Box 24)
    - SI: Congress, Vancouver, 1978 November 3-5, (five folders) (Box 24)
    - SI: Council, Cairo, Egypt, 1990 May 22-23, (three folders) (Box 24)
  - contents of Box 25: (Box 25)
    - SI: Council Meeting, Paris, 1988 December 5-10, (three folders) (Box 25)
    - Statement of Organization, VSDPC (Box 25)
    - Filing Reports, FEC (Box 25)
    - Organization Tax Forms (Box 25)
    - Leaflet Originals-Anti-Anderson Campaign (Box 25)
    - Young Social Democrats Political Committee (Box 25)
    - Benefit Journal, 1973 (Box 25)
    - Benefit, 1973 July 3 (Box 25)
    - Reunion, 1972 (Box 25)
    - Benefit Journal, 1976 (Box 25)
    - YPSL Benefit, 1976 (Box 25)
    - Benefit-Union Greetings, 1974 (Box 25)
    - Benefit-Union Greetings, 1975 (Box 25)
    - Benefit-Solicitation Letter (Box 25)
    - Benefit Leaflets of 1980 (plus sample from previous years) (Box 25)
    - YPSL Benefit Journal, 1978 (Box 25)
    - Benefits: Receipts (Box 25)
    - Benefits, 1978, (two folders) (Box 25)
    - YPSL Benefits, 1977 (Box 25)
    - Nixander: Correspondence (Box 25)
    - Anderson: September on Polls and Other Information. (Box 25)
    - Volunteers (Box 25)
    - Packets-Originals (Box 25)
    - Anderson: Publicity (Box 25)
  - contents of Box 26: (Box 26)
    Resleeve photographs; reformat newsprint and coated fax paper.
    - Statement of Organization, by Lauo (Box 26)
    - Nixander
      - Nixander: PAC (Box 26)
      - Nixander: Final Report to Labor (Box 26)
      - Nixander: Fund raising (Box 26)
      - Nixander: Correspondence Outgoing (Box 26)
    - Mail List for I.A.D Bulletin (Box 26)
    - Mail List (Box 26)
    - Photographs (Box 26)
    - Name Change Referendum (Box 26)
    - YSD Report, 1978 (Box 26)
    - YSR, 1971 November (Box 26)
    - YSR, 1972 (Box 26)
    - Rustin Concert (Box 26)
    - YPSL Benefit, 1980 (Box 26)
    - Benefit Greetings (INDVLS), 1980 (Box 26)
    - Journal Thank You's (Box 26)
    - Benefit Journal (Box 26)
    - Benefit Journal/Fund Raising, 1980 (Box 26)
    - Benefit Solicitation Letters, 1980 (Box 26)
    - Address List (Box 26)
    - Old Timers YPSL Fund (Box 26)
    - N.Y. Committee for Labor Youth (Box 26)
    - Schedules of Biggies (Box 26)
    - Benefit, 1976 (Box 26)
    - Benefit Printing, 1979 (Box 26)
    - Contributions - Industry and Fund Appeal (Box 26)
    - Benefit Journal, 1979 (Box 26)
    - Benefit Logistics, 1979 (Box 26)
    - Benefit Journal, 1985 (Box 26)
    - Benefit Journal, 1984 (Box 26)
    - Benefit greetings Organization, 1980 (Box 26)
    - TPSL Convention and School - 1974 Arrangement (Box 26)
    - Young Democrat Convention, 1978 (Box 26)
    - Convention, 1980 (Box 26)
    - Charter Dues Bill, 1975 June (Box 26)
    - Charter Dues Bill, 1976 (Box 26)
    - Coalition for a Democratic Majority 1975 (Box 26)
    - Coalition for a Democratic Majority, (five folders) (Box 26)
    - Committee for a Community of Democracies-USA (Box 26)
    - Committee to Explain the Fonda Syndrome (Box 26)
    - Committee of Correspondence (Box 26)
  - contents of Box 27: (Box 27)
    - Pledge Plan, (two folders) (Box 27)
    - Institute for Democracy in Eastern Europe (Box 27)
    - Indochinese Refugee Statement, (six folders) (Box 27)
    - Indochinese Refugees, (four folders) (Box 27)
    - Indochinese Refugee Resources Kit (Box 27)
    - International Youth Conference, Jamaica, 1985 (Box 27)
    - International Labor Affairs (Box 27)
    - International Association of Machinists (Box 27)
    - Industrial Policy Statement (Box 27)
    - Industrial Policy (Box 27)
    - International Communications Agency (Box 27)
    - International Center for Trade Union Reports (ICTUR) (Box 27)
    - International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers (Box 27)
    - Interco Press (Box 27)
    - Institute for Labor Education and Research (Box 27)
    - International Youth Year (Box 27)
    - Institute for Democracy in Vietnam (Box 27)
    - Institute on Religion and Democracy, File 2 (Box 27)
    - Industrial Policy Statement (Box 27)
    - Irving Louis Horowitz (Box 27)
    - Hoover Institution (Box 27)
    - Horak, Jiri (Box 27)
    - Housing (Box 27)
    - Howe, Irving 1993 (Box 27)
    - Howe, Irving (Box 27)
    - Henry J. Hymoff (Box 27)
    - Hudson Institute (Box 27)
    - Sidney Hook, (six folders) (Box 27)
  - contents of Box 28: (Box 28)
    - YPSL Resolutions--IUSY (Box 28)
    - 1975 IUSY Congress in Brussels (Box 28)
    - IUSY Minutes and Resolutions 1966-1970 (Box 28)
    - Randolph Evening 1971, (two folders) (Box 28)
    - IUSY Minutes and Resolutions 1971-1973 (Box 28)
    - IUSY Minutes and Resolutions 1977 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence 1977 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence 1976, (two folders) (Box 28)
    - Membership Project (Box 28)
    - Meeting February 27 (Box 28)
    - Mazur, Jay (Box 28)
    - Michael Massing (Box 28)
    - Meter Inspection 1999 (Box 28)
    - McReynolds, David 1993 (Box 28)
    - McGovern Amendment (Box 28)
    - Moira McDaid (Box 28)
    - McCurdy, Dave (Box 28)
    - Marathon Group (Box 28)
    - Marable, Manning (Box 28)
    - Bruce McColm (Box 28)
    - Herb Magidson (Box 28)
    - SI Mailing List for Memos (Box 28)
    - Madrid Conference 1980 (Box 28)
    - YPSL Benefit and Reunion 1971, (two folders) (Box 28)
    - YPSL Benefit and Reunion 1970, (two folders) (Box 28)
    - YPSL Reunion 1969 (Box 28)
    - YPSL Reunion Journal-- 1969 (Box 28)
    - YPSL Reunion 1967 (Box 28)
    - IUSY Explusion Proceedings (Box 28)
    - YPSL Expulsion: IUSY (Box 28)
    - Correspondence 1965-1969, (two folders) (Box 28)
    - IUSY Minutes and Resolutions 1975-1976 (Box 28)
    - IUSY, (two folders) (Box 28)
    - Correspondence 1970-1972 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence 1973, 1974, 1975, (two folders) (Box 28)
  - contents of Box 29: (Box 29)
    - IUSY Bulletin, 1968-1975, (two folders) (Box 29)
    - Conference on Democratic Socialism, Columbia University, 1976 October 7 (Box 29)
    - Constitution of the SDUSA (Box 29)
    - Venezuela Experience, Venezuela Pérez Inauguration, 1989 January 30-31, (two folders) (Box 29)
    - Vietnam, (two folders)
      - Vietnam 1993 (Box 29)
      - Vietnam 1974, (two folders) (Box 29)
      - Vietnam, File 2 (Box 29)
      - Doan Van Toai, (five folders) (Box 29)
      - Vietnam, The Institute for Democracy in (Box 29)
      - Vietnam Committee on Human Rights (Box 29)
      - Vietnam-- Tran Van Tuyen (Box 29)
      - Institute for Democracy in Vietnam Proposal, (three folders) (Box 29)
    - Western Sahara (Box 29)
    - Yugoslavia 1993-1994, (six folders) (Box 29)
    - Zaire (Box 29)
    - Zambia (Box 29)
    - Zimbabwe (Box 29)
  - contents of Box 30: (Box 30)
    This box contains legal size materials removed from previous boxes and videocassette tapes.
    Reformat newsprint and coated fax paper; make use copies of videocassettes.
    - Comentary (Box 30)
    - 1994 Convention Resolution (Box 30)
    - Alexander Cockburn (Box 30)
    - COIN-Consumers Opposed to Inflation and the Necessities (Box 30)
    - DSOC (Box 30)
    - Donald F. Cole (Box 30)
    - YPSL Benefit 1975 (Box 30)
    - Presidential Elections File 2 (Box 30)
    - Wash. Ed.-Winter-Spring 1986 (Box 30)
    - Application for IUSY (Box 30)
    - SI Chile Committee (Box 30)
    - SI Committee: LAtin American Caribean, Santo Domingo 1988 November 26-1988 November 27 (Box 30)
    - El Sal.-Freedom House Project (Box 30)
    - SD, Credo 1991-1992 (Box 30)
    - SI Chile Committee 1988 July 2-1988 July 3 Santiago, Chile (Box 30)
    - Venezuela (Box 30)
    - Grants (Box 30)
    - SI Nicaragua Mission 1990 January 12-1990 January 14 (Box 30)
    - YIPME Leaflet (Box 30)
    - Volunteers (Box 30)
    - Indochinese Refugees (Box 30)
    - International Youth Conference, Jamaica 1985 (Box 30)
    - Sidney Hook (Box 30)
    - 1975 IUSY Congress in Brussels (Box 30)
    - Notes on Expulsion by U. Parsh (Box 30)
    - Correspondence 1976 (Box 30)
    - YSPL Benefit and Reunion 1971 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence 1973, 1974, 1975 (Box 30)
    - Venezuela Pérez Inaguration (Box 30)
    - Vietnam Doan Van Toai File 3 (Box 30)
    - APRI a Portrait in Black, (video cassette) (Box 30)
    - Empower America, Empowering Our Public Schools: The Family Academy, Harlem, NY, (video cassette) (Box 30)
    - Labour Party Conference-British Labour Party Tony Blair (excerpts) 1996 October 1 (Box 30)
    - American Institute for Free Labor Development, "A Permanent People's Struggle", (video cassette) (Box 30)
  - National Committee Meetings, Conferences and Conventions--Audio cassette and data tapes
    Make use copies of all audio cassettes and data tapes in boxes 31-39.
    - contents of Box 31: (Box 31)
      - Nineteen cassette tapes (Box 31)
    - contents of Box 32: (Box 32)
      - Nineteen cassette tapes (Box 32)
    - contents of Box 33: (Box 33)
      - Nineteen cassette tapes (Box 33)
    - contents of Box 34: (Box 34)
      - Nineteen cassette tapes (Box 34)
    - contents of Box 35: (Box 35)
      - Seventeen cassette tapes and two QIC-2120 data tapes (Box 35)
    - contents of Box 36: (Box 36)
      - Fourteen cassette tapes (Box 36)
    - contents of Box 37: (Box 37)
      - Nineteen cassette tapes (Box 37)
    - contents of Box 38: (Box 38)
      - Nineteen cassette tapes (Box 38)
    - contents of Box 39: (Box 39)
      - Nineteen cassette tapes (Box 39)
  - Membership Cards/Dues Records 1955-1992; Member Rolodex Cards, undated (Box 40)
  - Applications for Membership in SDUSA, 1976-1994 (Box 41)
  - Vinyl records, (4 records and jackets) (Box 42)
    - Solidarity Day, 1982 (Box 42)
    - Groundwork: Songs of Working People, 1979 (Box 42)
    - Folk and Country Songs of the FDR Years, 1979 (Box 42)
    - Norman Thomas at 80, 1964 (Box 42)
  - contents of Box 43: (Box 43)
    - Photographs (Box 43)
    - Debs Award Dinner
      - Publicity and Speeches (Box 43)
      - Finances (Box 43)
      - Correspondence (Box 43)
      - Greetings (Box 43)
      - Dias (Box 43)
      - Invitations (Box 43)
      - Printed Materials (Box 43)
      - Lynn R. Williams (Box 43)
      - Ticket Sales (Box 43)
      - Hotel (Box 43)
      - Seating Plan (Box 43)
      - Sponsors (Box 43)
    - Debs Dinner Lists ( 1984-1986), (two folders) (Box 43)
    - 1986 Debs Award Dinner
      - Ticket Sales (Box 43)
      - Speeches (Box 43)
      - Dinner Seating Plan (Box 43)
      - Correspondence-General (Box 43)
      - Finances (Box 43)
      - Publicity (Box 43)
      - Edward J. Cleary (Box 43)
      - Greetings (Box 43)
      - Hotel/Party (Box 43)
      - Printed Material (Box 43)
      - Sponsors (Box 43)
      - Dias (Box 43)
    - 1987 Debs Dinner-- Jay Mazur
      - Speeches (Box 43)
      - Printed Material (Box 43)
      - Seating Plan (Box 43)
      - Dias (Box 43)
      - Hotel/Party (Box 43)
      - Finances (Box 43)
      - Lists (Not on Disk) (Box 43)
      - Correspondence/General (Box 43)
      - Greetings (Box 43)
      - Sponsors, (two folders) (Box 43)
      - Ticket Sales (Box 43)
      - Publicity (Box 43)
    - 1988 Debs Dinner Sandra Feldman
      - Ticket Sales (Box 43)
      - Seating Plan (Box 43)
      - Dias (Box 43)
      - Sponsors (Box 43)
      - Finances (Box 43)
      - Lists (Not on Disk) (Box 43)
      - Greetings (Box 43)
      - Hotel / Party (Box 43)
  - contents of Box 44: (Box 44)
    - 1988 Debs Dinner Sandra Feldman (cont.)
      - Correspondence/General (Box 44)
      - Publicity (Box 44)
      - Speeches (Box 44)
      - Printed Material (Box 44)
    - 1989 Debs Dinner, John Sweeny, Tikets Sales (Box 44)
    - Schools Project 1971 March (Box 44)
    - Socialist Party, (two folders) (Box 44)
    - University Labor Education Association (Box 44)
    - Vienna Institute (Box 44)
    - Vietnam Moratorium (Box 44)
    - YCPDME, (four folders) (Box 44)
    - YPSL (Box 44)
    - Projects (Box 44)
    - US Youth Council (Box 44)
    - United Federation of Teachers (Box 44)
    - UAW (Box 44)
    - Steering Committee Names (Box 44)
    - Ryan Cocktail Party, (two folders) (Box 44)
    - Special Contributors Mailing (Box 44)
    - Radical Sects (Box 44)
    - Milstein (Box 44)
    - DSOC (Box 44)
    - Debs Caucus (Box 44)
    - Progressive Action Society (Box 44)
    - Legal (Box 44)
    - Sales Tax Excemption (Box 44)
    - NY State Returns (Box 44)
    - Scholarship Fund (Box 44)
    - Coalition Caucus and Harrington, (three folders) (Box 44)
    - World Without War Council, (two folders) (Box 44)
    - Proposed Local Drops, 1972-1973 (Box 44)
  - contents of Box 45: (Box 45)
    - Resignations completed 1974-1975 (Box 45)
    - Harrington (Box 45)
    - Socialist Party Tendency Steering Committee (Box 45)
    - RSC and Steering Committee (Box 45)
    - AFT and NEA attacks on SD (Box 45)
    - NC Resignations, 1973 November 10 (Box 45)
    - Daily world clippings about SD, AFL-CIO and UFT, etc. (Box 45)
    - Resignations, pre-1971, A-Z, (5 folders) (Box 45)
    - New York Local YSD (Box 45)
    - Eric Chenoweth, (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - Anderson campaign (Box 45)
    - Young Social Democrats, (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - OSHA lobbying (Box 45)
    - New York University, September 1 ongoing (Box 45)
    - Columbia/Meetings, 1980 January 1 ongoing (Box 45)
    - USYC, (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - Columbia Chapter, September 1 ongoing (Box 45)
    - Eric Chenoweth, YSD (Box 45)
    - Energy/Nationalize Big Oil! (Box 45)
    - Leaflet originals, 1979 September 1 ongoing (Box 45)
    - New York YSD (Box 45)
    - USYC (Box 45)
    - Information requests (Box 45)
    - Labor contributions (Box 45)
    - Intra-organizational issues and reports (Box 45)
    - YSD organizing manual (Box 45)
    - International Youth Year Commission, (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - Recruitment, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - contents of Box 46: (Box 46)
    - Socialist Standard (Box 46)
    - Socialist Workers Party (Box 46)
    - International Union of Socialist (Box 46)
    - Socialist Women (Box 46)
    - Socialist International (Box 46)
    - SI: Meeting, Budafest, 1994 November (Box 46)
    - SD, in the News
      - 1992-1993 (Box 46)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 46)
      - 1983 (Box 46)
      - 1982 (Box 46)
    - Social Action (Box 46)
    - Socialist Affairs (Box 46)
    - Document on Social Democracy Send to the Following Address (Box 46)
    - Social Democrats, Burma (Box 46)
    - Social Democracy (Box 46)
    - Social Democratic Digest (Box 46)
    - Social Democracy Attacks (Box 46)
    - Dialogue: Social Democracy and the Economy (Box 46)
    - D. Slaiman, (two folders) (Box 46)
    - Lauren Slaiman (Box 46)
    - The Social Democrat (Box 46)
    - SD Conference (Box 46)
    - Singer, Max (Box 46)
    - Fanny Simon (Box 46)
    - Philip Siegelman (Box 46)
    - SI List (Box 46)
    - Committee in Support of Solidarity (Box 46)
    - Speakers (Box 46)
    - Speakers (Central America and the Caribbean) (Box 46)
    - Soviet Dissidents, (two folders) (Box 46)
    - Spartacist League/U.S. (Box 46)
    - Socialist and Social Democratic Theory (Box 46)
    - Second Thought (Box 46)
    - Schroeder, Julian (Box 46)
    - The Sanctuary Movement and the Jews (Box 46)
    - SI Reports (Box 46)
    - Socialist Party (Box 46)
    - Social Democratic Party (Britain) (Box 46)
    - Social Economic Policy (Box 46)
    - Dialogue: Social Democracy and the Economy (Box 46)
    - Socialism, (two folders) (Box 46)
    - Hugh Sheehan, 1994 (Box 46)
    - Sam Shube, 1993 (Box 46)
    - Selling Them the Rope, (two folders) (Box 46)
    - Albert Shanker
      - Albet Shanker (Box 46)
      - Higher Education: Albert Shanker Speech, (three folders) (Box 46)
  - contents of Box 47: (Box 47)
    - Max Shachtman, (three folders) (Box 47)
    - DSOC Convention Report (Box 47)
    - 1973 May (Box 47)
    - Application to Socialist International, by Harrington - DSOC, 1973 June (Box 47)
    - Affirmative Action (Box 47)
    - Abzug, Bella (Box 47)
    - Linda Chavez (Box 47)
    - Appeal to Reason Bulletin (Box 47)
    - Area of Concern (Box 47)
    - American Federation of Teachers, (two folders) (Box 47)
    - Mobilization, 1987 April 25 (Box 47)
    - Andrei Sakharov Defense Campaign (Box 47)
    - The American Spectator (Box 47)
    - Prodemca, (two folders) (Box 47)
    - Child Labor
      - Child Labor (Box 47)
      - Child Labor Abuse International, 1990 June (Box 47)
    - Eric Chenoweth (Box 47)
    - Leo Cherne (Box 47)
    - AFT-Task Force on Educational Issues, (two folders) (Box 47)
    - Michael Harrington
      - Harrington Resignation (Box 47)
      - Response to Harrington Resignation by NAC-SDUSA, 1973 July 20 (Box 47)
      - Harrington Resignation (mailings to NAC), 1973 (Box 47)
      - Harrington Resignation Letter, 1973 June 21 (Box 47)
      - Michael Harrington (Box 47)
      - Harrington (Box 47)
    - Daily World Series on SDUSA, 1976 June 20 - 1976 June 26 (Box 47)
    - Daily World, (two folders) (Box 47)
    - McReynolds (Box 47)
    - Socialist Party-Milwaukee Group (Box 47)
    - Personal (Box 47)
    - Factional stuff (Box 47)
    - Democratic Left
      - Clippings of Democratic Left, SDOC (Box 47)
      - Democratic Left (Box 47)
      - Democratic Left Newsletter, (List to get) (Box 47)
    - DSOC-Discussion Material, (two folders) (Box 47)
    - Full Report to NC (Box 47)
  - contents of Box 48: (Box 48)
    - Newsletter of the Democratic Left, (two folders) (Box 48)
    - Feldman- Gershman Campaign, 1971
      - Feldman- Gershman Campaign, (two folders) (Box 48)
      - Joint Campaign Committee, 1971 (Box 48)
      - Receipts or Thank You Letters, SP Campaign Fund, etc. (Box 48)
    - Caravatti, Marie Louise (Box 48)
    - Capitialism, Socialism, and Democracy (Box 48)
    - Andrei Sakharov Defense Campaign (Box 48)
    - Daniel Cantor (Box 48)
    - Bund, International Jewish Labor (Box 48)
    - Jewish Labor Bund (Box 48)
    - Rebel Song Book, Ramd School Press, 1935 (Box 48)
    - Helsinki and Human Rights, Andrei Sakharov, 1975 October 17 (Box 48)
    - Industrial Policy Statement, 1983 (Box 48)
    - Labor Challenges Nixon's Socialism For Rich and Free Enterprise for Poor (SP, 1971-1972) (Box 48)
    - Road Ahead, by Harry Laidler, 1950 (Box 48)
    - For the Record (Box 48)
    - Economics of Equality, by Tom Kahn ( L.I.D., 1964) (Box 48)
    - El Salvador Campaign, 1981 Committee to Defend Land Reform in El Salvador (Box 48)
    - Congress and Realignment-1964, by Dr. Alex Garber (Box 48)
    - To Build a Democratic Left (Box 48)
    - The American Challenge (Box 48)
    - The American Ultras (Box 48)
    - American and the World Crisis (Box 48)
    - Less Is Less, by Bayard Rustin (NY Times Magazine, 1974 May 2) (Box 48)
    - Society (Box 48)
    - Twilight of Capitalism; Review by Sidney Hook (New Republic, 1976 August) (Box 48)
    - Toward Separatism, or Equal Opportunity?: the Women's Rights Movements (SDUSA, 197?) (Box 48)
    - Two Socialists View the New Left, by William Allen (Box 48)
    - Portugal AD. (SDUSA, 1975) (Box 48)
    - Rewriting HIstory: the Labor Myth, by Thomas R. Brooks (Box 48)
    - A Challenge to the Democratic Party (Box 48)
    - Investment in Our Youth, Issue Paper, 1987 October (Box 48)
    - Hammers and Tongs, printed 1987 March (Box 48)
    - Trade (Box 48)
    - Affirmative Action in an Economy of Scarcity (Box 48)
    - SD Quarterly (Box 48)
    - The Nicaraguan Democratic Struggle Our Unifinished Revolution, SD Papers No. 8 (Box 48)
    - Selling Them the Rope ( 1979), SD Papers N0. 6, by Carl Gershman (Box 48)
    - Rebuilding the Democratic Party: A Matter of Principles, by Penn Kemble (Box 48)
    - Appeal to Reason (Box 48)
    - Cornell Revisited, by B. Rustin, (YPSL pre: 1974) (Box 48)
    - Come Home Democrats (C.D.M.), 1972 (Box 48)
    - Civil Rights: the True Frontier, by Tom Kahn (1963) (Box 48)
    - A Bum Rap? Blacks and Daniel P. Moynihan, by Carl Gershman (New Republic, 1976 April 10) (Box 48)
    - Bloodbath!, (SDUSA, YPSL, 1975?) (Box 48)
    - The Economics of Black Equality, (YPSL, undated) (Box 48)
    - Politics of Poverty, by M. Harrington (L.I.D., 1965) (Box 48)
    - The Defense of Man (YPSL, 1972) (Box 48)
    - The Black and the Unions, by Bayard Rustin (Box 48)
    - Politics of Pollution (YPSL, 1973) (Box 48)
    - The Program of the Democratic Socialist Federation of the U.S.A (Box 48)
    - The Social Democratic Challenge and a Response to Conservatism, SD Papers No. 5, by Leszek Kolakowski and Sidney Hook, 1978, (three folders) (Box 48)
    - After the Dominoes Fell, SD Papers NO. 3 (SDUSA, 1978) (Box 48)
    - Africa, Soviet Imperialism and the Retreat of American Power, SD Papers No. 2 (Box 48)
    - What We Believe, SDUSA, 1993 June (Box 48)
    - " 1993 February NC Adopting Why America Needs", (three folders) (Box 48)
  - contents of Box 49: (Box 49)
    - SD Quarterly
      - Volume 1 No.2 (Box 49)
      - Volume 1 No.3 (Box 49)
      - Volume 2, No.2 (Box 49)
      - Volume 3, No.1 (Box 49)
      - Volume 3, No.2 (Box 49)
      - Volume 3, No.3 (Box 49)
    - SI: Congress, Geneva, 1976 November 26 - 1976 November 28 (Box 49)
    - SI: Congress - 1972 Documents, (four folders) (Box 49)
    - SI: Congress Resolutions Committee, Madrid, 1983 February 10 (Box 49)
    - SI: Leader's Conference, Caracas, 1982 February 24 - 1982 February 25 (Box 49)
    - SI: Congress, Stockholm, Sweden, 1989 August 1, (two folders) (Box 49)
    - SI: Conference on Economic Democracy (Box 49)
    - SI: Conference, Latin America (Box 49)
    - SI: Conference on Southern Africa, Arusha, Tanzania
      - 1984 September 4 - 1984 September 5 (Box 49)
      - 1984 September 4 (Box 49)
      - 1983 June 17 - 1983 June 18 (Box 49)
    - SI: Conference of Latin America Political Leaders, 1981 March 1 (Box 49)
    - SI: Committee for Latin America and the Caribbean, Santo Domingo, Dominican Rep., 1986 April 2 - 1986 April 3 (Box 49)
    - SI: Committee for Latin America and the Caribbean SICLAC, Panama City, Republic of Panama, 1986 September 25 - 1986 September 26 (Box 49)
    - SI: Committee for Latin America and the Caribbean, SICLAC, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1985 May 28 - 1985 May 29 (Box 49)
  - contents of Box 50: (Box 50)
    - Eric Chenoweth, Correspondence (Box 50)
    - NYC Events (Box 50)
    - Polish Workers Campaign (Box 50)
    - National Action Committee, (two folders) (Box 50)
    - PWTF Resource MAterial and Notes (Box 50)
    - PWTF Summer Offensive (Box 50)
    - Summer YSD Activity (Box 50)
    - YSD Fall Preparations (Box 50)
    - NYU 1980-1981 (Box 50)
    - National YSD Fall 1981 (Box 50)
    - Youth for Energy Independence (Box 50)
    - NEC/NAC Minutes (Box 50)
    - Columbia 1980-1981, (three folders) (Box 50)
    - Columbia 1991, (two folders) (Box 50)
    - International Federation of Liberal and Radical Youth (Box 50)
    - A Brief History of SDUSA by Karl Toth (Box 50)
    - YPSL, History (Box 50)